Bamboo
竹子
Laundry-hanging rods
晾衣杆
Bamboo, laundry-hanging rods
竹子 晾衣杆
I'm home.
我回来了
UNCLE: YOU'RE FINE THE WAY YOU ARE
（舅舅：你这样就挺好）
GET HOME
（回家）
SOLD CHEAPER THAN A SCOURING PAD
（卖得比洗碗布还便宜）
75 MINUTES AGO
（75分钟前）
Fujimiya said she's coming later.
澄夏说她一会过来
Got it.
知道了
What?
怎么了？
Well, she is a nice girl.
她是个好女孩
Guess so.
应该是吧
She tried to cut you out of my life.
她还想把你赶出我的生活呢
TO THE UNCLE FROM ANOTHER WORLD
（致异世界归来的舅舅）
You've got mail.
有你的邮件
I know, but it's in English, so I ignored it.
我知道 但邮件是英语写的 所以我没管
Let's see. "Changes to the YouTube Partner Program."
我来看看 “油管合作伙伴计划的变更”
Didn't know you read English fluently.
我还不知道你能流利地阅读英文
No, I pasted it into a translation app.
不 我把内容粘贴到翻译应用里了
How convenient.
好方便啊
And? What does it say?
上面说的是什么？
Uncle, you're about to lose your job.
舅舅 你要失业了
What?
什么？
Early 2018.
2018年初
Many small YouTubers lost ad revenue.
很多油管小主播失去了广告收入
1,000 SUBSCRIBERS OR 4,000 HOURS
（一千名订阅者或者四千小时）
My uncle's channel wasn't no exception.
我舅舅的频道也不例外
STARTING BY FEBRUARY 20, 2018
（从2018年2月20日起）
FEBRUARY 19TH, MONDAY
（2月19日 星期一）
By the end of today, I need to reach 4,000 hours of watch time
在今天结束前 我的频道 必须达到四千小时的观看时间
and 1,000 subscribers.
并拥有一千名订阅用户
UNCLE FROM ANOTHER WORLD CHANNEL SUBSCRIBERS
（异世界归来的舅舅 频道订阅用户）
The watch time greatly exceeds the threshold.
观看时间大大超出了门槛
Why so few subscribers?
但订阅用户怎么这么少？
MIKECHAN: I JUST FOUND YOUR CHANNEL! AMAZING CGI!
（麦克陈：我刚发现你的频道！ 电脑特效很棒！）
UNCLE FROM ANOTHER WORLD IT'S NOT CGI. IT'S REAL MAGIC.
（异世界归来的舅舅 那不是特效 是真正的魔法）
PLEASE READ THE DESCRIPTION BEFORE YOU WATCH THE VIDEOS.
（在观看视频之前 请阅读说明）
RECENTLY, I'M IRKED BECAUSE MANY PEOPLE COMMENT
（我最近很恼火 因为很多人）
WITHOUT READING IT.
（不看说明就评论）
PLEASE MAKE THE INTERNET AN ENJOYABLE PLACE
（请遵守规定）
BY COMPLYING WITH THE RULES.
（让网络成为一片乐土）
@UNCLEFROMANOTHERWORLD UM, SURE
（@异世界归来的舅舅 当然了）
THERE HE GOES AGAIN
（他又来了）
I'M DONE BEING YOUR FAN ARE YOU TODAY YEARS OLD?
（我受够了当你的粉丝 你今天才知道吗？）
AGAIN POPS IS RED IN THE FACE HE MAKES UP HIS OWN RULES
（老爸的脸又红了 他自己定规矩）
-This is why! -What?
-原来如此！ -怎么了？
Your fans are unsubscribing because of your shitty replies!
你的粉丝之所以取消订阅 是因为你的回复太不客气了
But, Takafumi…
但是 敬文…
No buts!
别找借口！
-Anyway, we are in a tight spot. -Yes, we've got to figure something out.
-总之现在情况很不利 -是的 我们得想想办法
I haven't been like this since the Sealed City, Luvaldram.
离开封印之城卢瓦德拉姆之后 我再也没遇到过这种情况
Their defense magic was broken, and 1,000 legendary beasts were released.
他们的防御魔法被打破 一千只传说中的怪兽得以横行
Uncle,
舅舅
why do you mention such a fascinating tale in a moment of crisis?
你为什么要在危急关头 提到这么吸引人的故事？
Do you want me to tell you?
你想听听吗？
Of course I do.
当然想了
In a moment of crisis?
在危急关头？
It's your fault!
这都怪你！
Icuras elran.
伊库拉斯埃尔兰
Is this the Sealed City?
这就是封印之城？
What an enormous barrier.
多么雄伟的屏障
What is it blocking?
它在防御什么？
You don't know anything, do you?
你什么都不知道 是不是？
Do you have the brains of an orc?
你的脑子是不是跟半兽人一样？
An orc?
半兽人？
-Orc. -It's an orc!
-半兽人 -他是半兽人！
Do not panic.
不必惊慌
Yes, he looks exactly like an orc.
没错 他长得跟半兽人一样
But if he were a real orc,
但如果他真是半兽人
he would have perished the moment he stepped within the barrier.
在踏入屏障的那一刻就会灰飞烟灭
-That's true. -Is he still a human?
-这倒是真的 -他还是人类吗？
This world is ending.
这个世界要完蛋了
I agree.
我同意
Orc face, you're often in a spot as if hemmed in by Chu's army.
兽人脸 你经常陷入 类似被楚军包围的境地
Wait.
等等
Hemmed in by Chu's army?
被楚军包围？
The Elf girl used an idiom referencing Chu.
精灵女孩引用了楚国的典故
Wasn't Chu an ancient state in China?
楚不是中国古代的一个国家吗？
It must be the translation.
一定是翻译的问题
LANGUAGE MENU 1 JAPANESE - 2 GRANBAHAMAL
（语言菜单 1 日语-2 格兰巴哈马尔语）
Irg zag lar rarla…
伊戈札格伊阿而拉拉…
The verbatim translation is "Wail of Guben's army on the 10th day."
逐字翻译过来就是 “古本军队在第十天的哀嚎”
It doesn't make sense as is, so the magic adapted Japanese nicely.
这样说不通 所以魔法 把它很好地翻译成了日语
What is this interface?
这是什么界面？
I copied this feature from your video player.
我从你视频播放器复制过来的功能
Don't you want to hide your face?
你不想遮住脸吗？
No.
不想
It doesn't make me want to retch anymore now that I'm used to it.
我现在已经看习惯 都不想吐了
-I can tolerate… -Wow, a giant fruit.
-我可以忍受… -哇 好大的水果
It's an equa, a produce of the South.
这是鄂瓜 南方出产的
SEALED CITY LUVALDRAM THE LAND WHERE BEASTS RISE
（封印之城 卢瓦德拉姆 野兽出没之地）
This barrier protecting the city wards off mythical beasts
这道护城屏障能抵挡神秘的野兽
that dwell in the west of the Land Where Beasts Rise.
它们居住在野兽出没之地的西部
A barrier of this scale isn't built in one night.
这种规模的屏障绝非一夕之间能够建成
-Kilighd l'gid riolran… -The city's been a trading hub…
-基里格德伊基德里奥伊兰… -多亏了这道屏障 这座城市…
-…Kulosha l'gid riolran. -…for local goods,
-…库洛沙伊基德里奥伊兰 -…一直是本地商品的
all thanks to this barrier!
交易中心！
Look at the barrier!
快看屏障！
What did you do, Uncle?
你都干了些什么 舅舅？
I wanted to see if it would work.
我想看看屏障是否有用
-Look! -Beasts are coming!
-快看！ -野兽来了！
The cyclops!
是独眼巨人！
That's a Titan!
那是泰坦！
Can that be a cloud dragon?
难道那是云龙？
Bring the spell cards!
快去拿咒语卡！
Which ones?
拿哪些？
All of them!
都拿来！
I've only seen such terrifying monsters in the picture books
我只在老家的图画书里见过
from my hometown.
这么可怕的怪物
Approximately 1,000 monsters.
大概有一千只怪物
What do you think, orc face?
你觉得呢 兽人脸？
There are too many for us to handle.
数量太多 我们应付不了
We cannot prevent mass casualty.
大规模伤亡无法避免
That's correct.
没错
What an ugly face.
多么丑陋的脸
But you don't hide it.
但你却不加以遮挡
You are so awkward.
真是让人难为情
Such a fool.
傻瓜
Run.
快跑
I put it up again.
我重新竖起了屏障
What?
什么？
I asked the barrier-forming spirits to repair it and they did.
我让屏障修筑精灵予以修复 他们照办了
The spirits gave me a hell of a time for it.
精灵们为此让我受了不少罪
A hell of a time?
受罪？
We lived!
我们得救了！
But what was that?
可刚才那是什么？
I thought I saw something flashing.
我好像看到有东西闪了一下
Does it mean someone broke the seal?
这是不是说有人打破了封印？
Was it a beast?
是野兽吗？
A beast?
野兽？
You dropped this, Elf girl.
这是你掉的 精灵女孩
Thank you. It's ancient.
谢谢你 这是件古物
It's a legendary weapon, right? You've got to handle it carefully.
是传说中的武器 对吗？ 你得小心点 收好了
"Legendary sword" sounds cool,
“传说之剑”听上去很酷
but, at the end of the day, it's an antique.
但说到底也只是件古董而已
An antique.
古董
The barrier's not so different.
屏障跟以前没什么区别
No maintenance was performed for several centuries.
好几百年没有进行维护了
Some failure is inevitable.
不可避免会出现故障
I heard that barrier magic books are in the king's capital.
我听说屏障魔法书存放在国王的都城
What a close call, orc face.
真险啊 兽人脸
Why don't you tell them that I broke the barrier?
你为什么不告诉他们 是我打破了屏障？
You owe me dinner.
你请我吃顿饭
We'll call it even then.
然后我们就扯平了
I took off.
我偷偷跑掉了
Why the hell you did run?
你为什么要跑掉？
It's critical to deter these types of jerks
对于这种混蛋 在他们第一次想敲诈你时
from extorting on the very first attempt.
你就一定不能让他们得逞
Otherwise, you'll be a sucker forever.
否则你就永无出头之日了
All right, orc face. Next, fetch me some pastries.
好了 兽人脸 接下来去给我拿些点心
His skepticism runs deep.
他的疑心病很重啊
Ask the spirits.
去问问精灵
What are you doing?
你在干吗？
I thought I'd ask my viewers to subscribe.
我要让我的观众订阅频道
What?
什么？
I explained I need them to help by subscribing to my channel.
我跟他们解释了 我需要他们帮忙订阅我的频道
What a stupid thing you've done!
这么干太蠢了！
You're done if you show your weakness.
如果暴露出你的弱点 你就完蛋了
Those trolls will start a flame war and grill you to the bone.
那些喷子会发起谩骂 把你批得体无完肤
Internet trolls who make money from hating will come after you.
那些靠喷人赚钱的杠精会揪住你不放
You are finished!
你完了！
Uncle, you are so done!
舅舅 你彻底完了！
I SUBSCRIBED. KEEP GOING!
（我订阅了 加油！）
SINCE YOU ASKED…
（既然你开口了…）
You guys…
你们…
AWAITING UPDATES I'M ROOTING FOR YOU
（坐等更新 我挺你）
Unbelievable.
真不敢相信
I had only seen the worst of the social media community.
我只见过社交媒体社区最坏的一面
The Internet had a kind and supportive side I hadn't seen before.
互联网还有充满善意和支持的一面 这是我之前没见过的
Hello!
你们好！
Who's the skeptic here?
到底是谁疑心重啊？
Wow, we reached 1,000 subscribers! Yes!
订阅用户达到一千了！太棒了！
"Thank you, everyone."
“多谢各位”
Should I use a smiley emoji?
我是不是应该用个笑脸表情符？
Sure.
当然了
What's going on?
出什么事了？
ORC FACE QUICKLY TRANSFORM
（兽人脸迅速变形）
The aging, unemployed singles are becoming a serious social problem.
失业单身人士老龄化 正在成为严重的社会问题
For example, an unemployed uncle crashing at his nephew's place,
比方说 失业的舅舅在外甥家里借住
wrecking the young man's life.
破坏年轻人的生活
Unthinkable, right?
不可思议 对吧？
I totally agree.
完全同意
Wow, the new video already reached 10,000 views.
新视频的观看次数已经达到了一万
Is being a YouTuber considered a career?
在油管上当主播也算事业吗？
The revenue comes only from ads, right?
广告是唯一的收入来源 对吧？
Yeah.
对
That's a commonly asked question.
这个问题经常有人问
I'm a pro collaborating with a corporation,
我是跟企业合作的专业人士
so I can't disclose the details.
所以不能披露细节
Sorry.
抱歉
With a roommate…
有室友的话
Takafumi can't even consider living with a girlfriend.
敬文都无法考虑跟女朋友同居
Oh, yeah, Fujimiya. You should live here.
是的 澄夏 你应该搬来住
Takafumi's room sleeps two.
敬文的房间可以睡两个人
Wait!
等等！
-I don't mind sleeping on the floor. -Wait!
-我不介意睡在地板上 -等等！
Having two men in my room is a bit tight.
我房间里住两个人有点挤
It's not that spacious.
空间没那么大
Really?
是吗？
Sorry, I need to go out for a bit.
抱歉 我得出去一下
What? Wait!
什么？等一下！
Sugarless jam, 198 yen.
无糖果酱 198日元
That Takafumi.
这个敬文
Despite a wonderful girl such as you showing interest in him,
像你这样优秀的女孩对他有意思
he only sees you as a friend.
他却只把你当作朋友
Did something happen in the past?
以前是不是发生过什么事？
Huh?
什么？
-You can talk to me. -No, thank you.
-你可以告诉我 -不用 谢谢
Surely my experience of sacrificing my love countless times means something.
我曾经无数次牺牲自己的爱情 这种经历肯定还是有点用的
Kaede, at least go with my hands.
枫 至少牵着我的手走吧
Surely there are things only I can tell you.
一定有些只有我才能告诉你的事情
No way!
不可能！
I have nothing to confide to someone whose experience only comes from video games.
对一个恋爱经验仅仅来自电子游戏的人 我没什么好倾诉的
I'm not good enough for you.
对你来说 我还不够好
He is a weirdo.
他真是个怪人
But he has good intentions to try to bring us together.
但他想撮合我们 用意是好的
I was too harsh earlier.
我之前太过分了
What?
怎么？
Who… are you?
你是哪位？
I am Takafumi's aunt.
我是敬文的舅妈
His aunt?
他的舅妈？
Why is his aunt here?
他的舅妈怎么会在这里？
His uncle is here. Why not his aunt?
他的舅舅住在这里 为什么舅妈不能？
Where is Uncle?
舅舅去哪了？
He's in the bathroom.
他在卫生间
Help me, Spirit of Sound.
帮帮我 声之精灵
I'm here.
我在里面
Okay, let's talk.
好吧 我们来谈谈
-I mean, let's have a chat. -What?
-我是说聊聊天 -什么？
It's time for girl talk. No need to hold back.
到了女孩谈心的时间 不必遮遮掩掩
So, tell me, what happened in the past?
告诉我 之前出过什么事？
Nothing. Seriously, nothing happened.
没什么 真的 没什么事
I'm back.
我回来了
AND HERE WE ARE NOW
（到了现在）
It's Takafumi.
是敬文啊
Your aunt wants to give me relationship advice.
你舅妈想给我提一些恋爱方面的建议
What? My aunt?
什么？我的舅妈？
Relationship advice?
恋爱建议？
Uncle?
舅舅？
No, I'm your aunt.
不 我是你舅妈
Sonic and Tailz are--
索尼克和塔尔“兹”是…
No, it's Tails with an S.
不对 是塔尔“斯”
His real name is Miles Prower, but he goes by "Tails," as he has two tails.
他的真名是麦尔斯普劳尔 但他人称“塔尔斯” 因为他有两条尾巴
-Uncle. -I'm your aunt.
-舅舅 -我是你舅妈
You could have used this magic to change your appearance in the other world.
你可能在异世界里 就使用这种魔法改变过形象
Don't make it sound easy.
你说得容易
The mind gradually changes to conform to the body.
为了符合身形 大脑会逐渐发生变化
There is a risk that I can lose my identity.
我有可能会失去自我
Unless absolutely necessary,
除非万不得已
this magic is forbidden!
绝不能使用这种魔法！
And you are using it for a girl talk.
可你居然用来跟女孩说悄悄话
Well…
那好…
Whatever. Let's shoot a YouTube video.
无所谓 我们来拍段油管视频
No, now's not the time.
不行 现在不是时候
Fujimiya is here, so we should entertain her.
澄夏在这里 我们应该先招待她
Let's shoot a gaming video with Guardian Heroes.
我们来拍一段《守护英雄》的游戏视频
I'll do it!
没问题！
I've been wanting to shoot a gaming video.
我一直想拍游戏视频的
Yay!
太棒了！
We don't have time, so keep your face like that.
没时间了 所以你就保持这样吧
All right, let's get started.
好的 我们开始
What is going on?
这是怎么回事？
All right. The video is successfully uploaded.
好了 视频上传成功
I'm not as good as I once was but kept an entertaining play style.
我玩得没有以前好了 但游戏风格依然活泼有趣
I think we'll get tons of likes.
应该能收获很多赞
Can I see the video?
我能看看视频吗？
Uncle, before we get to that, we need to entertain Fujimiya.
舅舅 在这之前 我们得款待澄夏
Right, I forgot.
对 我都忘了
Uncle? Not aunt?
舅舅？不是舅妈？
All right.
好了
Let's review Takafumi and Fujimiya's earliest encounters.
我们来回顾一下敬文和澄夏初遇的情形
You cut right to the chase, Uncle.
你还真是直奔主题 舅舅
Let's start, Takafumi.
开始了 敬文
Spirit of Memory, show me a fragment of the recollections.
记忆之灵 显示回忆片段
-What the heck is this? -It's magic.
-这是什么？ -是魔法
Stop kidding me.
别逗我了
Oh, this must be a hologram! Right?
这一定是全息影像！对吗？
I've seen this in movies.
我在电影里见过
Yeah.
没错
This Sony machine projects the image here.
这部索尼机器会投射图像
So it's by Sony.
是索尼制造的啊
That's our elementary school before it was renovated.
这是我们翻新之前的小学
I bet you have erotic magazines stashed at home!
我敢打赌 你在家里藏了色情杂志！
I don't have them.
才没有
Wow, I want one of these devices.
哇 我也想要一款这样的设备
Don't talk back to me!
不许还嘴！
-Crap bomb punches! -Ouch, ouch!
-废话炸弹拳！ -哎哟！
Strange. Where is Fujimiya?
奇怪 澄夏在哪？
There's only a filthy brat.
只有一个下流的小毛孩
That's you, Fujimiya.
这就是你 澄夏
What?
什么？
Oh, I see. Yeah, that makes sense.
我明白了 是的 这就说得通了
What? Was I really like this?
什么？我真是这副模样吗？
I thought we had a more bittersweet childhood together.
我原以为我们在一起的童年 更像是甜蜜与苦涩交织呢
Here's poop.
臭臭来了
Wait, what?
等等 什么？
Fujimiya, I'm so sorry.
澄夏 很抱歉
This is hopeless.
这真是让人绝望
Don't watch it!
别看了！
Incredible of Takafumi to notice you when he saw you on the street.
敬文在街上看到你能认出来 真是难以置信
Of course I would.
我当然能认出来
I wouldn't forget Fujimiya.
我不会忘记澄夏的
Yeah, right.
是的 没错
Ouch. What's this for?
哎哟 这是干吗？
I see.
我明白了
It's not about the appearance.
外表并不重要
Had I been able to see that, maybe…
要是能早点明白的话 也许…
Oh, no.
不
Is this body affecting my mind?
这副躯壳影响到我的大脑了吗？
Please stop, Mr. Fujimiya.
求你住手 澄夏先生
-You called me Mr. Fujimiya. -Poop, poop!
-你叫我澄夏先生 -臭臭！
I seriously thought you were a boy for a while after we met.
在我们认识之后的一段时间里 我真以为你是个男孩
That's horrible!
太可恶了！
That's the video we uploaded just now.
这是我们刚刚上传的视频
VIRTUAL ELF YOUTUBER UNCLE
（虚拟精灵油管主播舅舅）
Virtual what?
虚拟什么？
Hi, guys! It's Uncle here.
你们好 各位！我是舅舅
Today, I want to do something a little different.
今天我想做件有点不一样的事情
Ta-da! I want to play a SEGA SATURN game,
快看！我想玩一款世嘉土星游戏
Guardian Heroes!
《守护英雄》！
Clap, clap, clap.
鼓掌
All right, for this video,
好了 在这段视频里
I'll play up to obtaining the hero's sword.
我要玩到获得英雄宝剑
To obtain the sword of Han's hero, select the bottom answer twice.
要获得韩氏英雄的宝剑 选择两次最下方的答案
Yep, it's that simple.
是的 就这么简单
All right, now…
好了 现在…
Wait a minute, Takafumi.
等一下 敬文
My game's screen isn't shown at all in the video we just shot.
我的游戏屏幕 根本就没出现在刚拍的视频里
Why would anyone watch this?
怎么会有人看这个？
Look at the view count. There's only…
看看浏览次数 只有…
NEW: VIRTUAL ELF YOUTUBER UNCLE
（新内容：虚拟精灵油管主播舅舅）
…200,000 views?
…二十万次观看？
We're going viral!
我们走红了！
This will be record-breaking! We'll hit three million views!
这将打破纪录！ 观看次数会达到三百万！
People don't want to watch a frowsy, old geezer!
人们不喜欢看邋里邋遢的老家伙！
It's the age of virtual YouTubers! Hot girl avatars!
现在是虚拟油管主播的时代！ 大家喜欢性感女孩头像！
SHIMA ARASHI: CUTE!
（岚志麻：好可爱！）
I'M A FAN - TOO CUTE
（我是粉丝-太可爱了！）
NO NEED FOR A GAME CONSOLE
（游戏机就用不着了吧）
You are all the same.
你们全都一样
-Yes! I was spot-on! -His nasty face appeared!
-太棒了！我的判断完全正确！ -他露出了那张讨厌的脸！
No!
不！
-We did it! -Gross!
-我们成功了！ -真恶心！
No!
不！
Uncle's pride as a YouTuber was torn to pieces.
舅舅作为油管主播的自豪感 遭到沉重打击
But on the payout date,
但在发薪日这天
a deluxe sashimi plate was served on our dinner table.
我们的餐桌上出现了一盘高级生鱼片
Subtitle translation by: Naoka Matsumura
字幕翻译：伍画